遠い… けど 全然　届かないわけじゃ　ない
He wouldn't ever let that thing beat him!
もっと　「念」を磨いて
So we should hurry back... Once we're stronger.
ヒソカに負けない力を 見つける！
To save Kite!
ミトさん！ ミトさん！
But before they can return to NGL, they must pass the condition
set by Chairman Netero, leader of the punitive force.
ミトさん！
What are those?
ゴン…。 ゴン！
You take a piece of marked wood and split it, giving each half to a different person.
ミトさん！
They work as proof that you're an ally or to authenticate a document.
ただいま　ミトさん！ おかえり　ゴン。
We sent two assassins to the nearest village.
あなたが　キルアね。 えっ？
In this case, each of the two assassins
holds one matching token.
いいよ　適当で。
It's been erased.
何　言ってんの！ せっかく　お友達も来てるのに。
That means someone checked the board.
いえ　お構いなく。
Yeah.
前もって　連絡ぐらい くれたらよかったのに。 エヘヘ…。 エヘヘ…。
You must be Killua and Gon.
聞いてんの？ エヘヘ…。
Nice to meet you.
あっ　そうだ ごはん作ってる間に お風呂　入んなさいよ。
My name is Palm.
服も全部　荷物から出しといてね 洗濯するから。 うん　後で。
It's a pleasure.
今！　１０秒以内！
Oh, dear...
１・２・３…。
No need to be so tense.
いつも　ああか？ 大体…　さっ　急ご！
I imagine the Chairman probably didn't provide many details. Allow me to explain.
あ　極楽　極楽。
I am a student of Knov-sensei.
さぁ　食事にしましょ。 すっげぇ　うまそう！
He said I would only get in his way...
ん？
Who's that? She probably means one of the
guys with Chairman Netero.
何？　これ。
My teacher is an incredible person.
恵みへの感謝さ。
Cool, intelligent, composed...
何だよ　それ。 じゃ　いただきましょう！
Ah, composed and cool mean the same thing! Oh, dear...
キルアも遠慮なく　たくさん食べてね。 はい。
Oh, but I only respect him, that's all. There's nothing romantic about my feelings...
そうだ　ミトさん。 ん？ 見て！
Ah, my teacher knows nothing
about this, of course.
これが　ハンターライセンスだよ。
I haven't said a word to him,
and I don't intend to.
えい！ わぁ！ 何すんだよ　もう！
No one can say what will happen...
冗談よ 本気でやるわけないでしょ。 もう　使えなくなったら どうすんのさぁ。
After all, love is a spontaneous thing, don't you agree? Uh, can I interrupt you?
ミトさん！　キルアに島の中を 案内して来るね。
Huh? Oh, dear... Yes, I apologize. The Chairman and my teacher
遅くなるんでしょ？ お弁当　作ろうか？
said I couldn't accompany them any farther.
いいよ！ 森で何か　とって食べるから！
But I insisted on going with them. It feels like I spent a lifetime just trying
to convince them of my determination.
久しぶりに帰って来たんだもの。
Knuckle and Shoot? Not us? That's right.
初めてのお友達を連れてね。
After all, I'm not the one who's
supposed to defeat Knuckle and Shoot.
帰って来るのは　きっと 夜　遅いわよ。
You two are.
そうだねぇ。
Knuckle and Shoot are Morel-san's students.
やっぱり　お弁当 持って行ってあげようかな
They, too, received a condition.
なぁ　ゴン。 ん？
But whether it's us or them, only one
group will be allowed into NGL. The deadline is one month.
お前　これから　どうする？ しばらくは　ここで ゆっくり休みながら 情報収集しようと思ってる。
Since we were told to keep
these tokens for a month, that means someone will come for them.
ふん　そっか…。
What do we do, Knuckle?
俺は　どうしよっかな。
He who strikes first, wins!
えっ？　キルアも　ここにいて 一緒にヨークシンに行こうよ！
Find 'em... And kill 'em! Certain Death
あぁ　もちろん行くけど そうじゃなくってさ。
My name is Knuckle Bine! I am a Beast Hunter!
お前　偉いなぁって話だよ。 えっ？
I challenge the two punitive
force candidates to a duel!
俺って　ないんだよなぁ。 お前みたいに　やりたいことがさ。
Come tonight at midnight sharp, and face me! Bring it on I won't try to run or hide.
やりたくないことなら 結構あるんだけどさ。
It'll just be me and me alone. So come and fight me!
家に　ずっといることとか。
But where? The location?
家業を継ぐこととか。
You have to tell them where to find you.
何か　うらやましいよ　お前が。
A man never turns his back on an enemy.
キルア。 ん？ 俺　キルアといると楽しいよ。
Bring it on I'll follow you to the ends of the Earth... You won't get away! Even if he said where, I wouldn't go.
なっ　何だよ　急に。
He's just a decoy.
この　くじら島ってさぁ
His partner's probably hidden
somewhere, watching.
出稼ぎの漁師が 長期滞在するための島なんだ。
They're watching to see if
anyone reacts suspiciously.
元からの島民は あんまりいなくて。 俺くらいの子供なんか 女の子が　たった一人だけ。
According to Palm, they don't
even know our names. Yeah.
だから　同い年の友達は キルアが初めてだったんだ。
So their goal must be to smoke us out. No one's stupid enough to do all that for real.
俺だって　そうだよ。
Did he look strong?
ずっと　家に こもりっきりでさ
He's pretty strong.
人殺しの技術ばっか 磨いてたからな。
What will it take to defeat him?
ゴンが初めてだぜ。
I have no idea!
キルアは　俺といて楽しい？
One of the Hunters with the Chairman said that
あ？
In a Nen battle, nothing is certain.
そりゃ　まぁ…　な。 じゃあ　これからも 一緒に　いようよ。 一緒に　いろんな所に行って いろんなものを見ようよ。
So, according to him, it's wrong for me to judge if a fight can be won. I disagree.
お前　ホント　恥ずいこと 平気で言うよな。
If you want to survive, you must
increase your odds of victory.
エヘヘ…。
Gauging the strength differential between
you and an opponent is crucial.
俺は親父を…。
If you're up against someone you can only beat
キルアは　やりたいことを探す旅！
once or twice out of a
hundred times, don't bother.
きっと　楽しいよ！
If possible, greater than
seventy percent is preferable.
フッ　そうだな
To reach that, we must do two things...
悪くないな。 よし！ やりたいことが見つかるまで
Work on our fundamentals, and learn
more about our opponents' abilities. Right.
お前の親父捜しに 付き合ってやるかぁ。 うん！
If we know our opponents' abilities,
it'll be easier to plan ahead.
ん？ ん？
Like we did against Genthru.
そういや お前のお袋さんって何してんの？
I'm half agreed, and half opposed. What do you mean?
親父のこと以上に 聞きづらいんだよね
Huh? Why not? That just increases our risk of defeat.
母親のことって。
Nothing good can come of that!
ずっと親代わりで 俺を育ててくれたわけだから
But that's what we'll be facing in NGL.
そういうこと聞くのって 何か　悪い気がしてさ。 そういうもんかな。
Our goal isn't to defeat Knuckle and Shoot...
ミトさんは最初 俺の両親は　「交通事故で死んだ」 って言ってたんだ。
It's to become stronger,
and return to NGL and save Kite.
親父が生きてて ハンターをしていることを知ったら 俺が親父みたいに なるんじゃないかって。
In other words, we must be strong enough to defeat
enemies we know nothing about.
心配した通りになったわけか。
Winning here with advance
preparation is pointless.
親父のことを知った時 何となく母親のほうは 本当に死んだんだろうなぁって 勝手に納得しちゃってさ！
That's true, After all, we only have a month.
ひでぇ話だな　そりゃ。
That's too long. One week.
俺にとって母親は ずっと　ミトさんだから。
In one week, we'll be stronger,
and heading back to NGL! Go—
他に　いないんだ…。
Are you an idiot?!
だから　聞くこともないし 聞く必要もない。
Bisky!
そっか。
Why are you here?
ああ　俺もミトさんみたいな 母親が　よかったなぁ。
I asked her to come. Huh? You know each other?
最高だよ ちょっと口うるさいけど。
No, I looked into your backgrounds. How? We only know Bisky because...
全然いいよ！ ウチのお袋なんてさ ちょっと出掛けようとするだけで わめくの何のって。
Once I used my power, it was quite simple.
ヒステリーだよ　ホント！ アハハハ…！
Now, there's no time to spare. Let's begin...
よいしょ。
Let's get started, then. Osu!
ねぇ。 何？ いつまで　ここにいられるの？
That old man's famous for his nasty nature.
うん　１か月くらいかな。
If he tells you to do something in a month, it probably should take an entire year. You won't defeat them after a week!
そしたら　俺…。 親父を捜しに行こうと思ってる。
But we have to hurry back and save Kite. What are you talking about?
ジンから預かったものよ。 えっ？ あなたが　ハンターになったら 渡してくれって…。
I'd love to fight you...
親父が　俺に…。
once more.
教えるわ。
I see...
私が　ジンについて 知っていること。
All the more reason you shouldn't
return without proper training!
ジンは　私の　いとこ。
So typical of her age. She's always ready with a lecture.
一番　古い記憶は　ジンの後ろ姿ね。
Got it? Osu...
走って行く彼の後に ついてく私。
Let's start training, then.
３つくらいだったかなぁ。
Begin with Ren!
今　思うと　いつも　あいつの 背中ばかり見てた気がする
Maintain that for three hours.
ジンがハンター試験を受けに この島を出たのは
Killua, how long can you last?
あなたと同じ　１２歳の頃だった。
In top condition, I can manage
around fifty-five minutes, max.
「何で？」って聞いたら たったひと言
Train like your lives are on the line!
私が一方的に わめいてたんだけど。
Come on.
それ以来　会わないまま ジンは島を出て行った…。
You didn't even last an hour. Okay, keep working.
「交通事故で死んだ」って 聞かされてたろ。 あれは　ミトの両親のことなのさ。
They say it takes a month to add ten
minutes to your Ren endurance.
えっ？ ジンが島を出て行って すぐのことでね。
You won't have time to sleep.
その後　今度は　ジンの父親が 漁に出たまま　行方不明になって。
Curses...
結局　私の息子は ２人とも死んでしまってね。
Those damn cowards ran away! You bastards deserve to die now!
ジンが島に戻って来たのは それから１０年後。
You have a collar. Where's your owner?
その時　あいつが抱えていたのが まだ赤ん坊だった　あなたよ。
You're supposed to keep the park clean. Okay, you can rest for today!
突然　帰って来たと 思ったら　いきなり 「この子を しばらく預かってくれないか」
Tomorrow begins in thirty minutes.
母親のことを聞いても 「別れた」の　たったひと言だけ。 私が「分かったよ」って 言い終わらないうちに
Looks like it's time for me to use my power.
だから　あなたの母親のことは 何も知らないの。
Take it away, Cookie-chan.
ミトったら　ジンに 「二度と帰って来ないで！」って 泣き叫んでねぇ。
Magical Esthetician: Piano Massage. Pink Relief
とにかく！　それは　その時 ジンが置いて行ったものなの。
Excuse me...
それも　何回 捨てられたか分からないよねぇ。
I hope this won't offend you, but I'll let you decide how to train them.
何回も捨てたのは おばあちゃんが拾って また同じ場所に戻すからでしょ！
Since my power told me that
you would be the answer.
家のゴミ箱に入れないで 埋めたり燃やしたりするものさ フン！
However, if they cannot defeat Morel's
disciples after one month, I doubt I'll be able to restrain myself.
分かった？ えっ？
I absolutely must go to NGL. Honestly, I want to depart this moment.
そんなものなの　私がジンについて 知っていることって。
So after I've waited and waited
and waited and waited and waited, if this fails now, I'll probably kill all of you...
ジン…。
Was that a threat?
ジンか…。
No, it's a warning.
ジン…　ジン！
I'm worried about you all.
うん！　やっぱり　いいや！ そっちのほうが。
So if you think they have no chance,
I recommend that you leave...
ねぇ　ミトさん　もっと聞かせてよ ジンが小さかった時の話。
Speaking from experience, I'm less
likely to lose my temper that way.
あれ？　やっぱり変かな？ 俺が言うと。
I'm not the one you should tell.
名前で呼んだほうが しっくり来るんだけど…。
Once they're awake, tell the boys.
ううん…　そうじゃなくて ジンの子供の頃の話でいいの？
Don't worry! We've got this!
うん！
You can count on us to get you to NGL.
ねぇ！　ジンには同い年の友達って いなかったの？
So let us know if you notice anything.
そうね…　いなかったわ。
We'll do our best.
子供は　私とジンだけ。
That's how they are.
だから　私は　あいつに 遊んでもらいたかったんだけど
Have some faith.
へぇ。
Oh, dear!
もう！ そんなことばっかり覚えてる。
This won't do at all...
ジンを追いかけて　山に入ったっきり 帰って来なくてね。
Anyway, I'm more concerned about
what's happening inside NGL.
ジンが１人で戻って来て
What is the Chairman's group
doing for the next month?
村中　大騒ぎなんてことが たびたびさ。
Well?! Ah, well... They mentioned they'd be poking and probing.
必ずジンが 最初に見つけちまうんだ。
Identifying the enemy's strengths,
and weakening their forces...
どんなとこで　ミトが じっとしててもね。
The experts can't agree on the amount of time
あんまり　それが続くから
remaining before the King's birth.
あんた達２人の いたずらじゃないかって 噂が出たほどだよ。 え！ そんなことするわけないでしょ！
The Chairman is operating with two months, the earliest prediction, as the deadline.
だって　あんたったら ホントに 見つかりにくい所にばっかり うずくまってるんだもの。
This is bad.
まるで　隠れてるんじゃないかって くらいにさ。
That thing is stronger than I am.
そうだったかなぁ。
Stronger than the Chairman?
そんなことも　あったっけ…。
Even when I'm at less than half my former strength? Growing old is no fun.
あっ　そういえば こんなこともあったわ…
He never stops talking. But we must fight.
へぇ なるほどね。
Our target is the Queen,
and the Queen alone. But sneaking past the surveillance of
that En will be next to impossible.
んで　これが　その箱な。 ん？　あれ？
We cannot avoid a fight...
これ　どうやって開けるんだ？
The question is how we will manage to win.
うん　いろいろ試したんだけど どうしても開かないんだ。
If anyone has any brilliant ideas,
I'd like to hear them.
ちょっと　力　入れていいか？ いいよ。 よし…　フンガ！
You're simply awful. When you asked us to join, did you not
already have an answer in mind?
うぅ…！ ダァ！　ハァ　ハァ。 ダメだな　普通の箱じゃねえよ。
We exterminate the Ants
in silence, one at a time.
ハンターになったら…　か。
Yeah, let's take it slow.
そうか…　分かった！
First, we should learn the enemy's numbers.
ゴン！　俺達　まだ 試してないことがあるぜ。
Go.
ハンターライセンス！
So many.
でも　カードの差し込み口とか どこにもないよ。
Something is coming.
いや　違うって…　「念」だよ　「念」。
They aren't alive...
あっ。
Is this the enemy's power? Now, what to do?
あっ！ あっ！
You have a point. These could be decoys.
箱の中に　また箱が…。 ああ。
No. I simply knew what you were thinking. Who are you, anyway?
ただの鉄っきれだ 全然　接着した跡もない。
One of the Queen's Royal Guard.
あっ。 どうしたの？
Shaiapouf.
そのデザイン　見覚えないか？ これって…　そうだ！ ウイングさんが　くれた 誓いの糸にも
Menthuthuyoupi will also soon awaken.
似たような模様が描いてあった。
Nyow I see. So you're Shaiapouf.
あれも確か 「念」を使うと切れるように 仕込んでたって言ってたよな。
Yes, that is correct. You can read all my thoughts.
どうやら　この模様には 「念」と似た力があるみたいだな。
Well, I can understand the sentiment.
もしかしたら　今度こそ このカードを差し込むのかも…。
But... He will wake soon.
見ろよ　指輪の裏にも あの模様があるぜ。 うかつには はめないほうがいいかもな。
Right, it's so simple.
そう？　それってジンが 俺に何かするかもってこと？
I merely need to fix him. I only need the power to do that.
じゃあ　まずは カセットテープから聞いてみる？ そうだな あっ　ダビングできるか？
And then, I will be able to experience
that dreamlike moment with you
できるよ　どうして？
once more...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　よう　ゴン。
N-No way...
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　やっぱり　お前も ハンターになっちまったか。
We never give up.
[ｽﾋﾟｰｶ]　それで　一つ 聞きたいことがある。
We must return to NGL, no matter
what we have to do to get there!
初めて聞いた　父親　ジンの声
To save Kite...
それは　まるで　ゴンの気持を 見透かすかのように 単刀直入に 問いかけて来るのであった
After reuniting with Bisky, Gon and Killua are back to training. They have one goal: